<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<cms.contentitemcommondata>
  <BaseContentShortDescription>
    <![CDATA[Learn about why I’ve made the source code for my personal blog site publicly available on GitHub.]]>
  </BaseContentShortDescription>
  <BaseContentTitle>Goldfinch.me is Now Open Source</BaseContentTitle>
  <ContentItemCommonDataContentItemID>
    <CodeName>Goldfinch.meIsNowOpenSource-sc33x623</CodeName>
    <GUID>cfba8eb9-a13b-44a3-8da4-bd1bdf233f9f</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.contentitem</ObjectType>
  </ContentItemCommonDataContentItemID>
  <ContentItemCommonDataContentLanguageID>
    <CodeName>en</CodeName>
    <GUID>22960170-5c33-4d4e-a01b-fd4c8fcbd13d</GUID>
    <ObjectType>cms.contentlanguage</ObjectType>
  </ContentItemCommonDataContentLanguageID>
  <ContentItemCommonDataFirstPublishedWhen>2025-08-10 21:45:14Z</ContentItemCommonDataFirstPublishedWhen>
  <ContentItemCommonDataGUID>732bdfb8-7668-48e2-b4be-71c06b3a8785</ContentItemCommonDataGUID>
  <ContentItemCommonDataIsLatest>True</ContentItemCommonDataIsLatest>
  <ContentItemCommonDataLastPublishedWhen>2025-09-12 21:41:32Z</ContentItemCommonDataLastPublishedWhen>
  <ContentItemCommonDataVersionStatus>2</ContentItemCommonDataVersionStatus>
  <ContentItemCommonDataVisualBuilderTemplateConfiguration />
  <ContentItemCommonDataVisualBuilderWidgets>
    <![CDATA[{"editableAreas":[{"identifier":"BlogPost","sections":[{"identifier":"674d2a89-8ce0-4cbe-9fcf-81d41ac98964","type":"Kentico.DefaultSection","properties":null,"zones":[{"identifier":"b623ac08-5ba7-4e88-879b-7c08e530dd6e","widgets":[{"identifier":"430efdf1-3ead-44d3-8e58-520433069d34","type":"Kentico.Widget.RichText","variants":[{"identifier":"d8399e3a-c8fd-4cf1-b56a-c95ec46f43dc","properties":{"content":"<p>For years, my blog website's source code has lived in a private Azure DevOps repository. It worked fine, but I've been thinking more about how I can share it directly with the wider Kentico community.</p><p>I often hear people check the Kentico Community Portal's <a href=\"https://github.com/Kentico/community-portal\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\">source code</a> as a way of seeing how to approach something, and I thought why not add to that by open-sourcing my own blog site.</p><p>So, earlier this month, I made the move. You can now access this website's code on GitHub in a <a href=\"https://github.com/liamgold/goldfinch.me\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\">public repository</a>. 🎉</p><p><strong>Why GitHub?</strong></p><p>The main reason is that it's simply easier for others in the community to discover and learn from projects hosted here.</p><p>But GitHub also brings some other great benefits. I can use the built-in security scanning, dependency tracking, a public issue tracker, and deeper integration with AI tools like GitHub Copilot.</p><p><strong>The Migration Process</strong></p><p>I didn't just copy and paste the source code into GitHub, there were a few things I needed to consider before making it public.</p><ul><li><strong>Git History</strong> - I started with a fresh git history. I didn't want to audit previous commits, and honestly... who knows what I committed a few years ago! 😅</li><li><strong>Remove connection strings</strong> - This one's fairly obvious. I didn't want to leak any database connection strings. Thankfully, I was already using a local database for development, and any preview/production databases are added during the deployment process.</li><li><strong>Remove CMSHashStringSalt</strong> - This salt is used for various security features in the platform, and exposing it publicly could open an avenue for exploitation.</li><li><strong>Review Continuous Integration (CI) files</strong> - My main concern here was ensuring my license key wasn't committed to source control. The rest of the CI files were safe to commit.</li></ul><p><strong>Where AI Helped</strong></p><p>When my source code was in a private DevOps repository, nobody was looking at the code other than me, so I didn't <em>really&nbsp;</em>need a README, did I? 🤔</p><p>Going open source meant I now needed one. Instead of writing it all manually, I let GitHub Copilot's Agent mode analyse the project and generate it for me. You can <a href=\"https://github.com/liamgold/goldfinch.me/blob/main/README.md\">see the result here</a>, and I think it's done a great job! 👏</p><p>I also used Copilot's Agent mode during the migrating process itself. After sanitising the project, I asked it to inspect and report back on anything that could be problematic to commit.</p><p>And, while we're talking about AI, I also recently tasked Agent mode with giving my website a visual refresh. The cards I use for blog posts and speaking engagements looked very basic, so Copilot rewrote them completely. You can see the <a href=\"https://github.com/liamgold/goldfinch.me/pull/6\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\">pull request here</a>.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p><p>Migrating to GitHub and open-sourcing my blog's source code can only benefit the community, and I'm glad I made the switch.</p><p>I'm excited to see how this might help other Kentico developers, and maybe even spark contributions or ideas for my own work.</p>"},"fieldIdentifiers":{"content":"fe0df84b-3b25-4051-b199-9f161cbcd087"}}]}]}],"fieldIdentifiers":{}}]}]}]]>
  </ContentItemCommonDataVisualBuilderWidgets>
</cms.contentitemcommondata>